Daniel Cox

Dartmouth, NS, Canda Phone: (902) 818 – 8129

Email: danielcox996@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/daniel-cox-b0320115b Website: https://dangerousdaniel.github.io/

ABOUT

I graduated from NSCC IT Programming (Class of 2020). For the last 2 years I've been developing a 2D fantasy platform game named Vex Monsters, where you save monsters from an evil mysterious villain.

Throughout my experience as a programmer, I have completed several challenging projects. These projects taught me a hands-on mindset and approach. I learned how to analyze, study, and apply learning to figure out solutions when working alone or with a team.

SKILLS

Unity, C#, Creative Writing, Project Management, Computer Maintenance, Software Installation, Computer Hardware, Responsive Web Design, Game Development, Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), Video Editing

TOOLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

C++, Python, Java, PHP, HTML, CSS, Windows, GitHub, Laravel, Google Suite, Trello, JavaScript, jQuery, Linux, Microsoft SQL Server, SQL, Microsoft Word, Adobe Photoshop

EDUCATION

IT: Programming

September 2018 – May 2020

NSCC IT Campus, Halifax, NS

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Developer

May 2022 - June 2022

Current Studios, Halifax, NS

- Worked with a team of front end and black end developers, QA and managers.
- Completed learning project of Node JS, and React JS.
- Scrum methodology
- Project: Re-build D&D Spells in React JS and Node JS:
- https://dangerousdaniel.github.io/dd-nodeJS.html

Senior Developer

November 2019 – March 2020

Nova Scotia Community College, Halifax, NS

- Lead team of 7 junior developers in handling various development tasks in support of IT Job Fair
- Front-end and back-end development in Laravel Framework
- Maintaining a Project Board on Trello and GitHub
- Website: itjobfair.ca

Junior Developer

April 2019 – May 2019

Nova Scotia Community College, Halifax, NS

- Assisted in developing an online trading card game.
- Developing the Home Page, Player's page, and responsive design
- This involved using HTML and CSS to create the website.
- The team used GitHub to assign tasks.
- Project: Digital Negotiator Spring 2019
- https://dangerousdaniel.github.io/dd-digitalNegotiatorSpring2019.html

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

Dishwasher/Link Cook September 202- Present, July 2016 – November 2018 Swiss Chalet, Dartmouth, NS

- Keep up a fast pace during rush hours to ensure adequate dishes are clean.
- Prepare setup and food for the day
- Use various cooking methods and equipment to specified recipes and standards
- Provide my employer with a flexible schedule, which allowed me to go into work on short notice.
- Maintain a neat and tidy workplace to ensure health and safety standards were met.

Dishwasher/Prep Cook

June 2021 - May 2022

Finbar's Portland Hills, Dartmouth, NS

- Working quickly to clean dishes and cooking equipment.
- Preparing food and ingredients to be used during service.
- Resupplying the kitchen when needed.
- Follow best safety practices and maintain a clean and safe work environment.

Line Cook

November 2018 - June 2021

Dairy Queen, Dartmouth, NS

- Successfully completed food safety training
- Prepare setup and food for the day
- Use various cooking methods and equipment to specified recipes and standards
- Follow best safety practices and maintain a clean and safe work environment
- Work independently and in a team environment

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Team Coordinator

September 2019 - March 2020

NSCC IT Job Fair & Conference- 2020, Dartmouth, NS

- Responsible for helping manage the team by tracking team minutes, participating in meetings, being a part of the leadership group and helping track loose ends.

IT Technician May 2017 - Present

Dartmouth Learning Network, Dartmouth, NS

- Diagnose computer problems, monitor computer processing systems, install software and perform tests on computer equipment and programs.
- Set up computer equipment, schedule maintenance and teach clients to use programs.
- Perform computer repairs and computer parts ordering.
- Maintain an inventory of over 40 computers.

MAMBEC Senior Instructor

March 2014 - June 2015

Martial Art Mind-Body Education Centre (MAMBEC), Dartmouth, NS

- Trained children in Martial Arts and self-discipline.
- Worked year-round on weekends, school professional development days and summer vacation.
- Completed over 500 Leadership/Volunteer hours.

Sales Clerk

September 2015 – June 2016

Common Values and Mort's Convenience, Dartmouth, NS

- Processed purchases and kept accurate records of daily sales.
 - Conducted monthly product inventory to allow sufficient stock to be ordered for the next month.
 - Ensured a tidy and safe work environment by completing a daily cleaning list.

PROJECTS

Vex Monsters

December 2019 – Present

- Vex Monsters is a fantasy platform game, where you save monsters from an evil mysterious villain.
- Team Leader
- Programming the logic and User Interface of the game from moving the player, AI, dialogue, NPC, and other game mechanics.
- Story Writer for the backstory
- Maintaining a Project Board on Trello
- Conduct weekly Scrums
- Learn more about Vex Monsters:
- https://dangerousdaniel.github.io/dd-vexMonsters.html

ADDITIONAL TRAINING & ACHIEVEMENTS

Challenge NS 2017 Second Place MAMBEC Martial Art Black Belt

2017

2012